



+918919296298



Praveenkusuluri08@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/praveen-kusuluri-0504a71b2

#### **GITHUB PROFILE**

https://github.com/PraveenKusuluri08

### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

**Programming Languages:** Python, JAVASCRIPT, GOLANG.

Frontend & Mobile: React.js, React Native

**Backend:** Node js, Express js, Redis, Firebase Admin, Golang mux and Gin.

**CSS Frameworks:** Material-UI, Bootstrap, Chakra Ui

State Management: Redux, Context API, Zustand

Databases: Mongo DB, Firebase Database

Version Control: Git, Bit bucket

Cloud and CI/CD: AWS, GitHub actions, Serverless and Fully managed application development

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

MERN bootcamp from LCO| MongoDB
University Certified in JavaScript by Hacker
rank Certified in Python by Hacker rank

### HOBBIES

Listening Music

Reading developers Blog Posts in Medium

Writing Code

Playing PS5 Games

**Work Samples** 

https://workforce.flairtechno.com/

# PRAVEEN SAI KUSULURI

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Experienced Full Stack Developer with nearly 2 years in developing Education, Legal, and Resource management domains. Demonstrated work experience in full-stack development, leadership abilities, and teamwork skills as well as the ability to accomplish tasks under minimal direction and supervision. I am always interested in learning new technologies and exploring new technologies that help me to build cost-effective and better optimum solutions for problems.

#### **EDUCATIONAL HISTORY**

# Sasi Institute of Technology and Engineering

Bachelor's in Technology | Jun 2019 Present Stream – Computer Science and Engineering CGPA – 8.5

# Sasi Junior college

MPC | 2017 - 2019

GPA - 9.5

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer

Eficens Systems | Legal and Immigration Services | July 2021 - June 2023

<u>Glance</u>: Complete management of employees starting from day to day attendance to payroll management.

# Role - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Implemented frontend user interface and features in the application using React JS, Redux, Material UI
- Developed backend using Node JS, Firebase admin sdk.
- Designed efficient serverless solutions using Firebase cloud functions
- Integrated Redux for better flow of data across the web application.
- Used Firebase provided NoSQL database to store data/transactions occurred in the application.

### Full Stack Developer

Eficens Systems | HR Software Development | Sep 2020 - July 2021

<u>Glance</u>: Automation of Visa processing documents.

# Role - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Implemented frontend user interface and features in the application using React JS, Redux, Material UI
- · Developed backend using Node JS , Firebase.
- Designed efficient serverless solutions using Firebase cloud functions.
- Provided cost effective solutions using serverless approach for the suitable problem.
- Implemented features like Profile Management, Employee Management, Timesheets Management, Expenses Management, Invoices Management, Deductions, Wiki, Placements Management, Clients Management, History logging, Letter Request Management etc.,

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

### **CHAT APP**

### Messaging

Role - Developer and Lead

Glance - A web application where users can create account and chat with different other people who are already created their account into app through email and users can interact with different other people in the groups.

Implemented frontend user interface and features in the application using React js, React Context API Chakra Ui for responsive designs and framer motions for cool animations.

- Developed backend using Node JS ,Mongoose ODM of MongoDB.
- Designed efficient and responsive and speed endpoint with Nodejs and Expressjs.
- Implemented Cost effective and scalable image upload to AWS S3 Bucket using Nodejs for entire application
- Used Soket.io for Bidirectional and low-latency communication between users when the message is published by the user to the
  another user.

### **ECOM-WEB**

### E-Commerce

Role – Backend Developer and Lead

Glance -A purely Backend web application which helps online business for to manage their selling products and publish products for customers as a Producer.

Technologies - Typescript, Nodejs, Express JS, Google Serverless Functions, Firestore, AWS SNS,SES.

• Features- Send Welcome Emails, Buy Products, Sell Products, Notify Users When new products are added by producer, Forgot password emails, Variable length Image uploads etc.

Code - https://github.com/PraveenKusuluri08/e-com

### GOLANG AUTH and Online EdTech

### **AUTHENTICATION & E-COMMERSE**

Role - Backend Developer and lead

Glance –Backend applications with Separate projects which uses Golang backend first one is Authentication using GOLANG GIN framework and Second one is Online EdTech Backend GOLANG, MongoDB and Gorilla MUX framework

Technologies - Golang, MongoDB, Gorilla Mux, GIN.

• Overview – Complex and advanced authentication system using Golang gin, Json web tokens and sessions for user logins and Second project Golang gorilla mux online courses EdTech platform.

Code - 1) https://github.com/PraveenKusuluri08/Golang-React-PR 2)

https://github.com/PraveenKusuluri08/golang\_mongoDB

#### **POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY**

- Full Stack developer for development of HR Software.
- Full Stack developer for development of Legal and Immigration Services Software.